exploreminnesota.com 2006-12-06

# Privacy Policy

### PRIVACY STATEMENT 

Explore Minnesota Tourism (EMT) is committed to maintaining a web site that protects the individual's right to privacy. We do not require personal information from our visitors, nor do we collect any personally identifying information (name, email address, Social Security number, or other unique identifier) unless you knowingly provide it. 

#### Information Collected from E-mails and Forms

You may decide to send us personally identifying information through on-line forms or e-mail messages. Electronic communication allows us to collect information that will allow us to provide you further services (e.g. ordering brochures or other information) and improve our web site for you. We use personally-identifying information from consumers in various ways to further our customer's protection and to provide better service.

#### Email Newsletters 

We offer several free travel information email newsletters. We do not provide the email addresses collected for these newsletters with other businesses or organizations, though future newsletters may include messages or advertisements from Minnesota travel businesses or organizations. There are two ways you may be subscribed to one or more of our newsletters: 1) you explicitly asked to be subscribed to a newsletter; or 2) you gave us your email address when requesting travel information in the past, and told us you would like to receive travel information in the future. Subscribing to any of our email newsletters requires positive confirmation from you by email, and options for unsubscribing from a newsletter are provided at the bottom of each newsletter.

#### Data Collection for Statistics

To aid in web site management, certain information is collected for statistical purposes. EMT uses specialized software to create summary statistics, which are used for such purposes as assessing what information is of most and least interest to our customers, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas.

Information we collect about your visit may include:

  *     the web site from which you linked directly to our web site, if you have used another web site to reach our site
 
  *     the IP address of the computer from which you connect to our pages
 
  *     the operating system and web browser you use to view pages
 
  *     the date and time you accessed our web site
 
  *     the pages you visit during your site
 
  *     the searches you execute

We use the information we collect to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our web site, allowing us to make our web site more useful and accessible to visitors. 

#### Cookies

Like many web sites, exploreminnesota.com makes use of cookies, pieces of information stored on your computer which allow our web servers to distinguish one visitor from another. We do not use these cookies to track your use of our web site individually, but rather 1) to allow you to use various personalization features of the site which require registration; and 2) to obtain aggregate measures of users of our site.

#### External links

We will link to external sites that help us perform our mission - "to promote and facilitate travel to and within the state of Minnesota." 

  *     Explore Minnesota Tourism provides links to individual tourism-related businesses and organizations within Minnesota. In addition, we reserve the right to provide links to external servers with whom Explore Minnesota Tourism is partnered or conducting promotional activities; or to sites that offer non-biased information that may be useful to those who travel in Minnesota.
 
  *     Links to external servers do not imply any official Explore Minnesota Tourism endorsement of the opinions or ideas expressed therein, or guarantee the validity of the information provided. Links to commercial sites are in no way an endorsement of any vendor's products or services. 
 
  *     Links will be provided to external servers that are managed in a professional manner (i.e., it is fully operational, is available most of the time, does not serve inaccurate information or obscene graphics, etc.). 
 
  *     This server will not link to external servers if such a link would appear to provide an official endorsement of a commercial product or business.
 
  *     All requests for links will be reviewed by Explore Minnesota Tourism's senior communications manager prior to approval.
 
  *     Placement of any link is at the discretion of Explore Minnesota Tourism.

#### Disclaimer of Accuracy or Endorsement 

Information on businesses and organizations within www.exploreminnesota.com is provided by those organizations, and is not verified or endorsed by Explore Minnesota Tourism. Users of this information are encouraged to call individual businesses to verify prices, amenities, features, dates and all other important details before traveling. Additionally, Explore Minnesota Tourism provides links to web sites which provide Minnesota travel information, but does not verify or endorse the content of any of those sites.

#### Copyright 

All information on exploreminnesota.com is protected by copyright by Explore Minnesota Tourism. Individuals are granted permission to view or print information on this website for travel planning or personal use, and may distribute this information to friends, family members or personal acquaintances for travel planning or personal use. 

Other uses of this information, including republication on the World Wide Web, in print publications, or in other formats/media, is not allowed without permission from Explore Minnesota Tourism.

Webmasters are welcome and encouraged to link to the Explore Minnesota Tourism travel information website from their own sites. Logos and suggested language for such links is available here.

#### Restrictions on using the Explore Minnesota Tourism logo

The Explore Minnesota Tourism logo is our official "trademark." Its use is reserved for official publications or other products of Explore Minnesota Tourism. Use of this logo without prior written approval is prohibited. 

  *     You must include the Explore Minnesota logo graphic with copyright (©) symbol intact, or the text ExploreMinnesota.com © with copyright symbol intact. 
 
  *     You must describe the link as the Explore Minnesota Tourism travel information website, or words to that effect. 
 
  *     Special permission is required for any other use of Explore Minnesota logos. For permission, and for access to print-quality electronic files, contact Bob.Erler@state.mn.us.
 
  *     Contact James Riemermann, 651/297-2077, james.riemermann@state.mn.us, with any questions. 

Last updated: November, 2006
